{
    "questions" : [
        {   "sections"      : "※ [1~3] 다음을 듣고 알맞은 그림을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "41_1_img",
            "option_1"      : "①  ",
            "option_2"      : "②  ",
            "option_3"      : "③  ",
            "option_4"      : "④  ",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Oh, why didn't you eat?\nMan : Let me see. I guess you didn't press the rice cooker button.\nWoman : That's weird. I definitely pressed it.......",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  ",
            "score"         : "2",
            "isImg"         : "y"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [1~3] 다음을 듣고 알맞은 그림을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "41_2_img",
            "option_1"      : "①  ",
            "option_2"      : "②  ",
            "option_3"      : "③  ",
            "option_4"      : "④  ",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Mr. Minsu, are you going to plant this here?\nMan : Yes. You just need to sell a little more, so hold it for a moment.\nWoman : OK But when I'm done planting, I'll have to give you a lot of water.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  ",
            "score"         : "2",
            "isImg"         : "y"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [1~3] 다음을 듣고 알맞은 그림을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "41_3_img",
            "option_1"      : "①  ",
            "option_2"      : "②  ",
            "option_3"      : "③  ",
            "option_4"      : "②  ",
            "detail"        : " Man : Everyone, have you ever lost your luggage or arrived late while using the plane? The number of plane baggage accidents from 2006 to 2014 was at its highest in 2010 and is declining, according to one report. Among the types of accidents, there were the most delays in the arrival of luggage late, followed by broken damage and loss of items in the bag.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  ",
            "score"         : "2",
            "isImg"         : "y"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [4~8]다음 대화를 잘듣고 이어질 수있는 말을 고르십시오.(각2점)",
            "question"      : "4. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  발표회는 언제 시작해요?",
            "option_2"      : "②  꼭 가려고 했는데 못 갔어요",
            "option_3"      : "③  도저히 시간이 안 될 것 같아요",
            "option_4"      : "④  갑자기 무슨 일이 있었던 거예요?",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Young-soo, did you finish the presentation well? I'm sorry I couldn't go.\nMan : no I heard there was something urgent.\nWoman : I really wanted to go, but I couldn't.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  꼭 가려고 했는데 못 갔어요",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [4~8]다음 대화를 잘듣고 이어질 수있는 말을 고르십시오.(각2점)",
            "question"      : "Q5. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  앞으로는 아껴 쓰면 좋겠는데요",
            "option_2"      : "②  용돈을 많이 주셔서 충분했어요",
            "option_3"      : "③  아직 남기는 했는데 살 게 있어서요",
            "option_4"      : "④  필요하면 언제든지 달라고 말할게요",
            "detail"        : "Man : Mom, I don't have enough pocket money, can you give me some more?\nWoman : (In a surprising tone) No, did you already finish what you gave me last week?\nMan : I'm still leaving it, but I have something to buy.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  아직 남기는 했는데 살 게 있어서요",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [4~8]다음 대화를 잘듣고 이어질 수있는 말을 고르십시오.(각2점)",
            "question"      : "Q6. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  이번에도 내가 이겼지?",
            "option_2"      : "②  내가 언제 그랬다고 그래?",
            "option_3"      : "③  배드민턴 치는 건 재미가 없어",
            "option_4"      : "④  계속 화내면 다시는 안 칠 거다",
            "detail"        : "Man : Sister, what are you doing? I'm bored, so let's go out and play badminton.\nWoman : good. But I'm not angry because I lost like last time.\nMan : When did you say I did that?",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  내가 언제 그랬다고 그래?",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [4~8]다음 대화를 잘듣고 이어질 수있는 말을 고르십시오.(각2점)",
            "question"      : "Q7. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  너무 바쁘셔서 그랬겠지요",
            "option_2"      : "②  준비하느라 많이 바빴겠어요",
            "option_3"      : "③  이렇게 초대해 주셔서 감사해요",
            "option_4"      : "④  집들이가 있는지 모르고 안 갔어요",
            "detail"        : "Man : Ji-young, you were invited to Kim Min-ho's housewarming party next week, right?\nWoman : Uh, that's right. Minho, let's have a housewarming party, right? I forgot.\nMan : It must have been because you were too busy.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  너무 바쁘셔서 그랬겠지요",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [4~8]다음 대화를 잘듣고 이어질 수있는 말을 고르십시오.(각2점)",
            "question"      : "Q8. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  그럼 언제쯤 신청서가 완성될까요?",
            "option_2"      : "②  그래요? 대회가 잘 끝나서 다행이군요",
            "option_3"      : "③  그래요? 학생들이 신청을 많이 했군요",
            "option_4"      : "④  그럼 기간이 좀 남았으니까 기다려 볼까요?",
            "detail"        : "Man : Mr. Lee, have you received a lot of applications for the Go competition?\nWoman : No, director. I handed out the application form to the students, but there aren't many yet.\nMan : Then there's some time left, so shall we wait?",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  그럼 기간이 좀 남았으니까 기다려 볼까요?",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [9~12]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 여자가 이어서 할행 동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "Q9. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  단추를 단다",
            "option_2"      : "②  셔츠를 준다",
            "option_3"      : "③  셔츠를 입는다",
            "option_4"      : "④  넥타이를 맨다",
            "detail"        : "Man : Honey, if you're not busy, please help me tie your tie. This doesn't tie well.\nWoman: OK. Huh? But the button fell off the shirt. I'll put it on soon, so give it to me.\nMan : Oh, here. I didn't see this It was okay when I wore it earlier.......\nWoman : It's right now. Wait a minute.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  단추를 단다",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [9~12]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 여자가 이어서 할행 동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "Q10. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  책을 읽는다",
            "option_2"      : "②  커피를 산다",
            "option_3"      : "③  산책을 한다",
            "option_4"      : "④  기숙사에 간다",
            "detail"        : "Woman : I'm so sleepy. There are still a lot of books to read.......\nMan : If you're sleepy, go into the dormitory, go to bed early, and wake up in the morning.......\nWoman : I can't get up early because I have a lot of sleep in the morning. I need to go out for a walk so I can wake up. Do you want me to buy some coffee when you come in, senior? \nMan : No, it's okay. I drank a while ago",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  산책을 한다",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [9~12]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 여자가 이어서 할행 동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "Q11. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  서류를 복사한다",
            "option_2"      : "②  홍보부에 다녀온다",
            "option_3"      : "③  부장에게 연락한다",
            "option_4"      : "④  사진을 거래처에 보낸다",
            "detail"        : "Man : Where have you been? The manager kept looking for it.\nWoman : I went to the public relations department to get the documents for a while. Why did you find it.\nMan : You came to check that the picture you sent to the client is different from the product. Please contact me as soon as possible.\nWoman : OK. Then please make a copy of this document.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  부장에게 연락한다",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [9~12]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 여자가 이어서 할행 동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "Q12. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  업체에 전화한다",
            "option_2"      : "②  주문서를 확인한다",
            "option_3"      : "③  재료를 창고로 옮긴다",
            "option_4"      : "④  빠진 재료를 알려 준다",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Kim Min-soo, did you get the food ingredients for today? \nMan : Yes, I came in a little while ago. By the way, chef. There are some things that didn't come in while I was organizing them, what should I do?\nWoman : If you let me know what's missing, I'll check the order form again and call the company.\nMan : Yes. Then I'll move the ingredients in front of the cooking room to the storage warehouse first.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  주문서를 확인한다",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [13~16] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "Q13. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  남자는 어머니의 블라우스를 산 적이 있다",
            "option_2"      : "②  남자는 오늘 어머니와 백화점에 갔다 왔다",
            "option_3"      : "③  여자는 상품권을 선물로 드리고 싶어 한다",
            "option_4"      : "④  여자는 오늘 어머니 선물을 사러 갈 것이다",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Brother, shall we go to the department store today and buy a present for mom? How about clothes?.\nMan : Would she like it? She don't wear the blouse I bought you last time. Why don't you give a gift certificate rather than clothes?\nWoman : Rather than that, it's best for mom to see it and choose it herself.......\nMan : Then let's take him next weekend.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  남자는 어머니의 블라우스를 산 적이 있다",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [13~16] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "Q14. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  첫 번째 일정은 도서관 방문이다",
            "option_2"      : "②  마지막으로 갈 곳은 체육관이다",
            "option_3"      : "③  식사 후에 기념품을 받을 수 있다",
            "option_4"      : "④  기숙사를 둘러본 후 동영상을 본다",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Thank you for visiting our university. I'll tell you briefly about today's schedule. First, you will watch the school introduction video for about 20 minutes in the auditorium, and then look around the library, gymnasium, and dormitory. And if you eat at the student cafeteria in the basement of the dormitory, the schedule will be over. When you go back, please be sure to pick up the souvenirs we prepared at the entrance of the restaurant.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  식사 후에 기념품을 받을 수 있다",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [13~16] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "Q15. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  다친 사람은 치료를 받고 귀가했다",
            "option_2"      : "②  승용차 두 대가 충돌해 사고가 났다",
            "option_3"      : "③  안개 때문에 사고가 난 것으로 보인다",
            "option_4"      : "④  사고 운전자들에 대한 조사는 끝났다",
            "detail"        : "Man : The following is the news of the accident. There was an accident where a truck and a passenger car collided on the road near Inju around 6 this morning. In this accident, the driver of a truck and a man in his 20s in a passenger car were injured and are being treated at Inju Hospital. The police believe that there was an accident because they couldn't see ahead due to the thick fog. We are investigating the drivers to find out the cause of the accident more accurately.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  안개 때문에 사고가 난 것으로 보인다",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [13~16] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "Q16. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  여자의 아들은 이 일을 하는 것에 반대했다",
            "option_2"      : "②  여자는 30년 동안 문화재 알리는 일을 했다",
            "option_3"      : "③  여자는 퇴직하기 전부터 이 일을 하고 있었다",
            "option_4"      : "④  여자는 지역 문화 센터에서 매주 강의를 한다",
            "detail"        : "Man : You are working to inform local cultural assets after you retire. Do you have any particular reason for doing this work?\nWoman : I've been teaching for 30 years and taught history. I was thinking about how to spend my old age after I retired. However, my son strongly recommended this work to make use of my experience. So, since last month, every Sunday, the Cultural Center has been giving a lecture introducing our local cultural assets.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  여자는 지역 문화 센터에서 매주 강의를 한다",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [17~20] 다음을 듣고 남자의 중심 생각을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "Q17. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  아이들은 다치면서 크기 마련이다",
            "option_2"      : "②  놀이터 시설을 관리할 필요가 있다",
            "option_3"      : "③  아이들은 놀이터에서 뛰어 놀아야 한다",
            "option_4"      : "④  아이에게는 조심하라고 주의를 줘야 한다",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Minho was injured again while playing at the playground during the day. I'm so upset that the kid keeps getting hurt. I shouldn't send it to the playground.\nMan : I got hurt while playing, but what are you doing? If you fall and get hurt like that, be careful not to fall next time. Wouldn't it grow up like that?\nWoman : But I'm worried because the kid keeps getting hurt.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  아이들은 다치면서 크기 마련이다",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [17~20] 다음을 듣고 남자의 중심 생각을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "Q18. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  대중교통을 자주 이용하도록 해야 한다",
            "option_2"      : "②  대중교통을 이용할 때는 불편해도 참아야 한다",
            "option_3"      : "③  대중교통 안에서는 다른 사람에게 피해를 주면 안 된다",
            "option_4"      : "④  대중교통에서 물건을 잃어버리지 않도록 잘 챙겨야 한다",
            "detail"        : "Woman  : Ugh, look at this. I was scratched by the person who was standing in front of me on the subway earlier. Do I have to carry my bag back like that?\nMan : I know. People carrying backpacks need to be careful. When using public transportation, it's good to turn the bag and hug it forward, or put it under the bridge or on the shelf.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  대중교통 안에서는 다른 사람에게 피해를 주면 안 된다",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [17~20] 다음을 듣고 남자의 중심 생각을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "Q19. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  공중전화의 설치를 늘려야 한다",
            "option_2"      : "②  휴대 전화 사용 시간을 줄여야 한다",
            "option_3"      : "③  휴대 전화가 있으면 급할 때 사용할 수 있다",
            "option_4"      : "④  공중전화는 급할 때 필요하므로 없애면 안 된다",
            "detail"        : "Woman : There's still a pay phone. I thought it was gone now.......\nMan : What are you talking about. I have to use it when I'm in a hurry, but I can't do it without it. There must be people who don't have a cell phone.\nWoman : You can borrow a cell phone from someone else when you need it, who's going to use a pay phone?\nMan : But there may be situations where you can't borrow it.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  공중전화는 급할 때 필요하므로 없애면 안 된다",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [17~20] 다음을 듣고 남자의 중심 생각을 고르십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "Q20. 2점",
            "option_1"      : "①  번역할 때는 한국의 정서를 반영해야 한다",
            "option_2"      : "②  번역은 원작의 표현을 그대로 옮겨야 한다",
            "option_3"      : "③  주인공의 성격에 중점을 두고 번역해야 한다",
            "option_4"      : "④  번역가는 높은 수준의 어휘력을 갖춰야 한다",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Sir, you moved a world-famous novel to Korean this time. You have heard that it was well expressed according to the situation in Korea. What part did you focus the most on during this work?\nMan : I thought it was important not to feel translated as much as translating it into Korean exactly. So in this work, I made a lot of hard work to express the main character's personality and relationship with the characters in accordance with Korean sentiment.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  번역할 때는 한국의 정서를 반영해야 한다",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [21~22] 다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "Q21. 남자의 중심 생각으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  매년 고객들의 반응을 살펴야 한다",
            "option_2"      : "②  이벤트 행사 준비는 빠를수록 좋다",
            "option_3"      : "③  반응이 좋은 행사는 반복하는 것이 좋다",
            "option_4"      : "④  전과 다른 새로운 행사를 기획해야 한다",
            "detail"        : "Man : Manager Lee, it's Chuseok soon. How did you plan the Chuseok event? This Chuseok is earlier than last year, so we need to prepare in advance.\nWoman : This time, like last year, I'm thinking of holding an event to give one more if I buy ten gift sets from a month before Chuseok. Last year, the customer's response was pretty good.\nMan : Isn't that the event been going on for years, not just last year? Don't do the same this year, plan a new event.\nWoman : Yes, I got it. I'll be ready and let you know by next week.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  전과 다른 새로운 행사를 기획해야 한다",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [21~22] 다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "Q22. 들은 내용으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  여자는 새로운 행사를 기획했다",
            "option_2"      : "②  작년 추석에 한 행사는 효과적이었다",
            "option_3"      : "③  남자는 다음 주까지 보고를 해야 한다",
            "option_4"      : "④  올해도 작년과 같은 행사를 할 것이다",
            "detail"        : "Man : Manager Lee, it's Chuseok soon. How did you plan the Chuseok event? This Chuseok is earlier than last year, so we need to prepare in advance.\nWoman : This time, like last year, I'm thinking of holding an event to give one more if I buy ten gift sets from a month before Chuseok. Last year, the customer's response was pretty good.\nMan : Isn't that the event been going on for years, not just last year? Don't do the same this year, plan a new event.\nWoman : Yes, I got it. I'll be ready and let you know by next week.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  작년 추석에 한 행사는 효과적이었다",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [23~24] 다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "Q23. 남자의 중심 생각으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  회의 장소를 추천하고 있다",
            "option_2"      : "②  회의장 시설을 점검하고 있다",
            "option_3"      : "③  호텔 위치에 대해 알아보고 있다",
            "option_4"      : "④  회의장을 빌리려고 문의하고 있다",
            "detail"        : "Man : That's the Seoul Hotel, right? I'd like to reserve a meeting room.\nWoman : Yes, customer. Which conference room are you looking for?\nMen : It's okay if we can fit about 100 people. The conference hall is equipped with a computer and microphone that can be used for presentations, right?\nWoman : Sure. There is a large conference hall that can accommodate up to 150 people. And every conference hall is equipped with the necessary facilities for the presentation. If you use the conference hall, drinks will be provided free of charge. If you visit us in person to look around the place, we will consult you in detail.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  회의장을 빌리려고 문의하고 있다",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [25~26] 다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "Q24. 들은 내용으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  회의장을 이용하면 음료가 할인된다",
            "option_2"      : "②  대규모 회의장에만 컴퓨터가 설치되어 있다",
            "option_3"      : "③  100명 이상이 들어갈 수 있는 회의장은 없다",
            "option_4"      : "④  직접 방문하면 더 자세한 설명을 들을 수 있다",
            "detail"        : "Man : That's the Seoul Hotel, right? I'd like to reserve a meeting room.\nWoman : Yes, customer. Which conference room are you looking for?\nMen : It's okay if we can fit about 100 people. The conference hall is equipped with a computer and microphone that can be used for presentations, right?\nWoman : Sure. There is a large conference hall that can accommodate up to 150 people. And every conference hall is equipped with the necessary facilities for the presentation. If you use the conference hall, drinks will be provided free of charge. If you visit us in person to look around the place, we will consult you in detail.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  직접 방문하면 더 자세한 설명을 들을 수 있다",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [25~26] 다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "Q25. 남자의 중심 생각으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  자연 환경보다 사람의 안전이 우선이다",
            "option_2"      : "②  자연과 사람이 어울려서 살아가야 한다",
            "option_3"      : "③  안전을 우선하다 보면 환경이 훼손될 수도 있다",
            "option_4"      : "④  사람이 자연을 즐길 수 있는 방법을 찾아야 한다",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Despite the opposition of some environmental groups, you recently installed a ladder on the top of Inju Mountain. Why did you install it in a hurry?\nMan : The top of Inju Mountain is a place where sliding accidents often occur due to the large number of rocks and severe slopes. That's why I decided that there must be a ladder to prevent accidents for hikers. It is also true that there were voices against it because the natural environment was damaged and the surrounding scenery deteriorated. But we put the safety of hikers first. We expect more hikers to visit Inju Mountain in the future.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  자연 환경보다 사람의 안전이 우선이다",
            "score"         : "2"
        },
        {   "sections"      : "※ [25~26] 다음을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 2점)",
            "question"      : "Q26. 들은 내용으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  사다리 설치 문제에 모두가 동의했다",
            "option_2"      : "②  과거 인주산에서 안전사고가 발생했다",
            "option_3"      : "③  경관을 위해 등산을 금지하자는 의견이 있었다",
            "option_4"      : "④  앞으로 인주산을 찾는 등산객이 감소할 것이다",
            "detail"        : "Woman : Despite the opposition of some environmental groups, you recently installed a ladder on the top of Inju Mountain. Why did you install it in a hurry?\nMan : The top of Inju Mountain is a place where sliding accidents often occur due to the large number of rocks and severe slopes. That's why I decided that there must be a ladder to prevent accidents for hikers. It is also true that there were voices against it because the natural environment was damaged and the surrounding scenery deteriorated. But we put the safety of hikers first. We expect more hikers to visit Inju Mountain in the future.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  과거 인주산에서 안전사고가 발생했다",
            "score"         : "2"
        }
        
    ]
   
}
